Finding Aid for the Collection of Material about National Socialism in Germany and the United States LSC.0338
UCLA Library Special Collections
National Socialism in Germany and the United States collection of material
1933-1965
UCLA Library Special Collections
LSC.0338
7.0 Linear Feet (14 boxes and 5 oversize boxes)
Restrictions on Access
Open for research. All requests to access special collections materials must be made in advance using the request button located on this page.
UCLA Catalog Record ID
UCLA Catalog Record ID: 9942327723606533
Scope and Content
Collection consists of pamphlets, newspapers, books, magazines, pictures, photographs, filmstrips, slides, ephemera, and objects relating to the Nationalsozialistische Deutsche Arbeiter-Partei in Germany and National Socialism in the United States. Includes handbills, posters, prints of watercolors by Adolf Hitler, SS banners, collages on wood, and filmstrips for the Hitler Youth. Also includes antisemitic materials from the U.S., and radio scripts by Upton Closes.
Organization and Arrangement
Arranged in the following series:
Zeitungsdienst (Boxes 1-5).
Books and pamphlets in English (Boxes 6-7).
Books, pamphlets, and ephemera in various languages (Box 8).
Mitarbeiter des Preussisches Justigministers, photograph album (Box 9).
Sketches, pictures, and printed propaganda (Boxes 10-11).
SS banners, collages on wood (Box 12).
Filmstrips, slides, negatives, and photographs (Boxes 13-14).
U.S. Anti-semitism (Box 15).
Miscellaneous neo-Nazi ephemera (Box 16).
Books in German (Box 17).
Newsclippings, photographs, and magazines (Box 18).
Freude und Arbeit magazine, 1941 (Box 19).
National socialism -- Archives.; Newspapers.; Fascism -- Archives.; Nationalsozialistische Deutsche Arbeiter-Partei.
- Zeitungsdienst: Deutschlanddienst., May 1943-February 1945. (Box 1)
- Zeitungsdienst: Auslandsdienst., February-June 1943. (Box 2)
- Zeitungsdienst: Auslandsdienst., February-June 1943. (Box 3)
- Zeitungsdienst: Auslandsdienst., February-June 1943. (Box 4)
- Zeitungsdienst: Auslandsdienst., February-June 1943. (Box 5)
- Berlinerdienst., April-October 1943. (Box 5)
- Books, etc. English
  - Heiden, Konrad. Der Fuehrer... Boston: Houghton Mifflin., 1944. (Box 6)
  - Billingsley, Chris. The Nazis called me traitor. New York: Exposition Press., 1965. (Box 6)
  - Trevor-Roper, H.R. The last days of Hitler. New York: Exposition Press., 1965. (Box 6)
  - Schneiderman, Harry, ed. The American Jewish year book 5697. Philadelphia: Jewish Publication Society., 1936. (Box 6)
  - [No author given]. The Man who killed Hitler. New York: MacMillan Company., 1947. (Box 6)
  - Stewart, A.H. and R.B. Eames. Will Hitler rule the world? No!... Los Angeles: Jewish Hope Publishing House., 1941. (Box 6)
  - Hitler, A. Germany declares for peace. Berlin: Liebheit & Thiesen., 1933. (Box 6)
  - [No author given]. The Anti-semitic and Nazi incidents. Bonn: The Government of... Germany., 1960. (Box 6)
  - Stieve, Friedrich. What the world rejected... n.p., n.d. (Box 6)
  - Hitler, Adolf. My battle. Houghton Mifflin., 1933. (Box 6)
  - Schadewaldt, Hans, compiler. Polish acts of atrocity against the German minority in Poland. Berlin: Volk und Reich Verlag., 1940. (Box 6)
  - Tolischus, Otto D. How Hitler prepared. Reprint from New York Times Magazine:, June 16, 23, 30, 1940. (Box 6)
  - Grunfeld, Judith. Mobilization of women in Germany. New York: New School for Social Research., 1942. (Box 6)
  - Paechter, Heinz. Nazi - Deutsch. New York: Frederick Unger Publishing., 1944. (Box 6)
- Books and Pamphlets, English
  - Facts in Review., 8 issues. (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Newspaper clippings. (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Miscellaneous ephemera. (Box 7, Folder 3)
- Books, Pamphlets and Ephemera
  - Various languages: German, Italian, Greek, Spanish, Portuguese, Dutch. (Box 8)
- Kerrl, Hanns. Mitarbeiter des Preussisches Justigministers. n.p. Photograph album., n.d. (Box 9)
- Propaganda
  - Printed color sketches of scenes on the Western front. (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - Pictorial material., 60 prints in folio. (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - Handbills, posters, brochures and newspapers., March-June 1944.; 4 albums. (Box 10, Folder 3)
- Adolf Hitler. Leipzig., 1936.; Pictorial scrapbook. (Box 11)
- Deutschland erwacht. Berlin., 1933.; Pictorial scrapbook. (Box 11)
- Prints of watercolors by Adolf Hitler., 1 folio. (Box 11)
- Oversize newspaper article. (Box 11)
- SS (?) banners, one with skull & crossbones patch., 2 items. (Box 12)
- Collages on wood., 2 items. (Box 12)
- Filmstrips for the Hitler Youth. (Box 13)
- Filmstrips, slides, negatives, and photographs. (Box 14)
- U.S. Anti-Semitism - Books and Pamphlets
  - Newspaper clippings. (Box 15, Folder 1)
  - Miscellaneous ephemera. (Box 15, Folder 2-3)
- Miscellaneous neo-Nazi ephemera. (Box 16)
  Scope and Contents note
  Includes Upton Close's Closer Ups (vol.1-2). September 1945-January 1947. Also, radio scripts. February 1946-January, 1947.
- Books, German
  - Hartnake, Dr. Wilhelm. Die Ungeborenen. Munehen: Lehmanns verlag., 1936. (Box 17)
  - ----, ----. Grosse Deutsche Kunstansstellung 1938. Munchen: Verlag F. Bruckmann KG. (Box 17)
  - ----, ----. Grosse Deutsche Kunstausstellung 1939. Munchen: Verlag F. Bruckmann KG. (Box 17)
  - Erbt, Wilhelm. Weltge schischte anf rassischer Grundlage. Leipzig: Urmanen - Berlag., 1936. (Box 17)
  - Hoff, R.D. Kasse. Berlin: Berlag von BG Tenbner., 1934. (Box 17)
- Newsclippings, photographs and magazines., 1934-1945. (Box 18)
- Magazine. Freude und Arbeit (Joy and Work)., 1941.; 1 item. (Box 19)